

#### MACHINE LEARNING SPECIALIST

Aarhus, Denmark

【 (+45) 2991 3001 ☑ Tue.Boesen@protonmail.com ☑ tueboesen 🞓 Tue Boesen

# Summary\_

I am a machine learning scientist and have previously worked as: software developer, researcher, project lead, and technical advisor/consultant on various projects. I have a solid foundation in: physics, mathematics, data science, and high-performance-computing. I am familiar with programming best practices and generating production-ready code. Within machine learning, I have specialized in physics-informed and graph neural networks, but I have experience with most areas of deep learning, and I have applied machine learning in many different fields.

# Selected experiences

MACHINE LEARNING HIGHLIGHTS

NEURAL SOLUTIONS

- Developed novel **physics-informed graph neural networks** that allow the consideration of constraints and symmetries, and used them on mechanical and molecular systems to lower constraint violations by several orders of magnitudes, while increasing prediction accuracy.
- Developed novel **active learning** techniques for image classification and used them to significantly lower the amount of training images required for high accuracy.
- Developed novel clustering techniques to more accurately predict oil and mineral concentrations in the ground.
- Built **natural language processing** and **convolutional** models and used self-training to teach them how amino acids bind together and how proteins fold.
- Used transfer learning and reversible networks to create geological maps from satellite data.
- Used reinforcement learning and Monte Carlo graph search techniques to create Als that can play boardgames.

Owner – Consultant Aarhus, Denmark

Scoping of business problems solvable by machine learning.

· Designed tailored neural network architectures.

#### **Lead Machine Learning Specialist**

Vancouver, Canada

Dec 2021 - Nov 2022

PROTEIC BIOSCIENCE INC.

Jan 2022 - June 2022

- · Lead developer of equivariant twice-differentiable neural networks for biomolecules.
- Developed MLOps framework with MLflow and Optuna for automatic data ingestion, processing and feature transforms, hyperparameter tuning and model tracking.

### **Postdoctoral Research Fellow in Machine Learning**

Vancouver, Canada

University of Bristish Columbia (UBC)

May 2019 - Aug 2021

- Developed novel physics-informed neural networks inspired by differential algebraic systems of equations capable of honoring constraints and symmetries.
- Published reversible mimetic graph neural networks.
- · Developed self-supervised conditional probability neural networks inspired by natural language processing models.
- Published a semi-supervised active learning algorithm utilizing pseudo-labeling which offers theoretical guarantees to be optimal.
- Deployed large-scale training on Amazon Web Services.

Al Research Scientist Vancouver, Canada

COMPUTATIONAL GEOSCIENCE INC.

May 2019 - Aug 2020

- Developed clustering techniques for oil exploration.
- Published novel graph-based semi-supervised learning methods applied to seismic data.

Research Assistant Aarhus, Denmark

HYDROGEOPHYSICS GROUP AT AARHUS UNIVERSITY

Aug 2017 - Nov 2017

- Open-sourced a sparse iterative parallel linear solver based on my research during my Ph.D.
- Open-sourced an OpenMP parallelization framework developed during my Ph.D.

#### **Analyst, Graduate Position**

Copenhagen, Denmark

DANSKE BANK

Sep 2013 - Apr 2014

· Worked in customer insight creating forecast models.

Software Developer

Aarhus, Denmark Mar 2013 - Sep 2013

HYDROGEOPHYSICS GROUP AT AARHUS UNIVERSITY

Created SPIA, an application for ground-based electromagnetic measurements.

**Education** 

Ph.D. in Geophysics Denmark

 AARHUS UNIVERSITY
 2015 - 2018

• Thesis: Numerical methods for electromagnetic geophysics beyond 1D

#### M.S. in Theoretical Physics

Denmark

 Aarhus University
 2010 - 2011

 Thesis: Foundation for a parallel time-dependent density functional theory simulator in a spherical harmonic basis using the exact exchange energy functional

B.S. in Physics Denmark

AARHUS UNIVERSITY 2006 - 2010

· Thesis: Feynman's path integral in one dimension with focus on sinusoidal trajectories

### Skills

Platforms Windows, Linux Ubuntu, AWS

Programming Python, Pytorch, LaTeX, Git, Matlab, Fortran, Julia, Delphi/Pascal, OpenMp, MPI

Languages Danish, English

# Teaching and supervision.

**Teaching**Aarhus University, Denmark

INSTRUCTOR 2009-2017

· Calculus.

- Electric and Electromagnetic methods.
- · Data processing and interpretation for groundwater mapping.
- · Geophysical methods.
- Hydrogeophysical field course (twice).

**Supervision** UBC, Canada

CO-SUPERVISOR 2020

• Jingrong Lin – Ph.D. student in geophysics and machine learning.

## **Publications**

#### **Submitted**

Neural DAEs: Constrained neural networks Tue Boesen, Eldad Haber, Uri M Ascher arXiv preprint arXiv:2211.14302 (2022). 2022

#### **Journal Articles**

A-optimal active learning

Tue Boesen, Eldad Haber

Physica Scripta 98.4 (Mar. 2023) p. 045014. IOP Publishing, 2023

Mimetic neural networks: a unified framework for protein design and folding

Moshe Eliasof, Tue Boesen, Eldad Haber, Chen Keasar, Eran Treister

Frontiers in Bioinformatics 2 (2022). 2022

Data-driven semi-supervised clustering for oil prediction

Tue Boesen, Eldad Haber, Michael G Hoversten

Computers & Geosciences 148 (2021) p. 104684. Pergamon, 2021

An efficient 2D inversion scheme for airborne frequency-domain data

Tue Boesen, Esben Auken, Anders V Christiansen, Gianluca Fiandaca, Casper Kirkegaard, Andreas A Pfaffhuber, Malte Vöge Geophysics 83.4 (2018) E189–E201. Society of Exploration Geophysicists and American Association of Petroleum ..., 2018

A parallel computing thin-sheet inversion algorithm for airborne time-domain data utilising a variable overburden Tue Boesen, Esben Auken, Anders V Christiansen, Gianluca Fiandaca, Cyril Schamper

Geophysical Prospecting 66.7 (2018) pp. 1402-1414. European Association of Geoscientists & Engineers, 2018

A review of airborne electromagnetic methods with focus on geotechnical and hydrological applications from 2007 to 2017 Esben Auken, Tue Boesen, Anders V Christiansen

Advances in geophysics 58 (2017) pp. 47-93. Elsevier, 2017

### **Conference Proceedings**

Semi-supervised clustering for oil prospectivity Tue Boesen, Eldad Haber, Michael G Hoversten ICLR Al for Earth Sciences workshop, 2020

Efficient 2D hybrid inversion of airborne frequency domain data

Esben Auken, Tue Boesen, Anders V Christiansen, Gianluca Fiandaca, Andreas A Pfaffhuber, Malte Vöge Second European Airborne Electromagnetics Conference, 2017

2D FEM inversion with a moving footprint and a hybrid 1D and 2D forward and derivative implementation
Tue Boesen, Esben Auken, Malte Vöge, Casper Kirkegaard, Kristoffer Andersen, Andreas A Pfaffhuber, Anders V Christiansen

AGU Fall Meeting Abstracts, 2016

Utilizing massively parallel co-processors in the AarhusInv 1D forward and inverse AEM modelling code Casper Kirkegaard, Kristoffer Andersen, Tue Boesen, Anders V Christiansen, Esben Auken, Gianluca Fiandaca ASEG Extended Abstracts, 2015

Rapid inversion of large airborne AEM data datasets utilizing massively parallel co-processors Casper Kirkegaard, Kristoffer Andersen, Anders V Christiansen, Esben Auken, Tue Boesen First European Airborne Electromagnetics Conference, 2015

2.5D inversion of sea ice thickness from helicopter EM data Malte Vöge, Andreas A Pfaffhuber, E Auken, Casper Kirkegaard, Tue Boesen, Stefan Hendricks, Priska Hunkeler First European Airborne Electromagnetics Conference, 2015

### About me\_

My main hobbies outside work are boardgames, rock climbing and beach volley. Apart from those I like to tinker with various projects, my current project is to **develop a framework** that can play various boardgames, while previous ones include: building a quadcopter, and designing and building a hangboard with a CNC machine and laser cutter.